Guide to the Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Land and Plantation Records, 1689-1855; Series III; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series III, Land and Plantation Records, contains deeds, royal warrants, mortgages, leases, official inventories, quitclaims, wills, annuity grants, articles of purchase, and other conveyance documents concerning properties on various Caribbean islands. These have been arranged first by island, then by property name, and finally chronologically within each property. Documents relating to properties on multiple islands have been listed at the beginning of the series. Information concerning the persons named in a document has been provided wherever it was readily available, whether from a docket or from the document text. In most cases, we do not have a complete title series for any given property, nor is it always clear why a specific document is found in the Lavington Papers, although in many cases a member of the Payne family or a related family is named. Nevertheless, these provide valuable information concerning West Indian plantation ownership and business dealings. Many of the documents are or contain detailed inventories: there are at least sixteen slave inventories in this series, from several islands across seven decades. Occasionally there is a fairly full accounting of the history of a property. Box 5, folders 150-161 contains documents relating to Carlisles, once one of the richest plantations on Antigua, from an early inventory of "field negroes" to the legal maneuvering that resulted in Baron Lavington's eventual inheritance of the property, to the multiple "sales of Negroes" in the 1790s that financed Lavington in London. (The final mortgage on Carlisles is located in Box 5, folder 150). The largest number of documents is from Lavington's native St. Kitts. Many from the 1720s relate to the final expulsion of the French from St. Kitts by the Treaty of Utrecht and the British crown's attempt to regularize land titles in the conquered area of Basseterre: hence the many "articles of purchase" between island residents and "His Majesty." Indentures and rental agreements for smaller plantations on both St. Kitts and Nevis also contain valuable information about the economic and social status of non-slaveholding white settlers, while the mortgage and annuity contracts reveal the often ruinous loan terms agreed to by cash-poor owners. Folders 178-180 contain documents related to the St. Croix sugar plantation founded by Ralph Payne and Alexander Cooper.
  - Multiple Islands
    - Deed of trust from Sir Ralph Payne to Godschall Johnson, 1786 Dec 1
      Plantations in St. Christopher's and Antigua; includes a schedule of slaves
    - Surrender of trust from Godschall Johnson to Sir Ralph Payne and Deed of Trust from Sir Ralph Payne to Messrs. Nesbitt and Stewart, 1789 Dec 31
      Plantations in St. Christopher's and Antigua; includes schedules of slaves and livestock for both
    - Deed of covenant between Lord Lavington and Daniel Bergeman, 1798 Jul 27 (Box 5, Folder 150)
      Mortgage of plantations in St. Christopher's and Antigua
    - Conveyance from Lord Lavington and others to William Farmerie in trust, 1801 Jun 25
      Multiple lands in England
  - Antigua
    - Carlisles
      - "A List of Field Negroes belonging to Francis Carlile", 1728 Aug 20 (Box 5, Folder 151)
      - Will of Francis Carlisle (incomplete), undated (Box 5, Folder 152)
        Disinheriting his "undutiful daughter Alice Payne"
      - Letter of attorney from Elizabeth Carlisle to Mackinnon, Tomlinson and Payne (2 copies), 1744 Oct 12 (Box 5, Folder 153)
      - Special letter of attorney from Elizabeth Carlisle to Ralph Payne, 1744 Oct 12 (Box 5, Folder 154)
      - Release by way of settlement from Elizabeth Carlisle to Ralph Payne, 1744 Oct 12 (Box 5, Folder 155)
      - Articles of agreement between John and Elizabeth Carlisle Gray and Ralph Payne for obtaining an Act of Assembly concerning the plantations in Antigua, 1752 Dec 26
      - Royal Proclamation of the Act of Assembly concerning the plantations in Antigua, 1754 Jul 21
      - Accounts for "Carlile's Plantation", 1773-1774 (Box 5, Folder 156)
      - "A List of Negroes Cattle Horses Mules Buildings Utensils &c on the estate in Antigua called Carliles...", 1774 Jan 1
      - "Coppy List of Sir R. Paynes Negroes etc.", 1779 Aug 15 (Box 5, Folder 157)
      - "A General List of Negroes belonging to Sir Ralph Payne K.B. upon his estate called Carliles...", 1780 Dec 8 (Box 5, Folder 158)
      - "A General List of Negroes belonging to Sir Ralph Payne K.B. upon his estate called Carlisle...", 1781 Oct 25 (Box 5, Folder 159)
      - "A General List of Negroes belonging to the estate of Sir Ralph Payne K.B. called Carliles...", 1783 Apr 25 (Box 5, Folder 160)
      - "Sales of Negroes belonging to the Right Honourable Lord Lavington...", 1796-1797 (Box 5, Folder 161)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 425
  - Barbados
    - "Major Clarke's estate at the Bell in Barbados...", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 162)
      Brief descriptive inventory
  - Dominica
    - Indenture for Princess Plantation from Henry Curry and Levy Porter to John Thornton, 1772 Feb 6 (Box 5, Folder 163)
      Includes inventory of slaves
  - Montserrat
    - Indenture and conveyance from Bartholomew Rees to Rowland Tryon and William Tryon of sugar works and plantations on Montserrat, including "Calk Hill", 1705 May 8
      Includes attestation by Thomas Sandiford
    - Indenture and conveyance from William Tryon to Robert Cunningham of two sugar works and plantations on Montserrat, Cork Hill and a plantation in St. Anthony's Parish, 1732 Feb 9
      Includes inventory of Cork Hill slaves
  - Nevis
    - Brodbelt Plantation
      - Memorandum of mortgage by lease and release from James Brodbelt to Stephen Payne in 1769 (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 164)
      - Assignment of mortgage of Brodbelt plantation from Sir Ralph Payne to Ralph Willett: draft (2 copies), 1775
    - Charles Town land
      - Grant from King George II to Ralph Payne, 1757 Mar 7
    - Sweetens Land and Mountain Plantation
      - Indenture from James and Perletta McSheen to Ralph Payne (2 copies), 1746 Jan 8, 27 (Box 5, Folder 165)
      - Indenture from James and Perletta McSheen to Ralph Payne, 1747 Dec 4 (Box 5, Folder 166)
      - Indenture from James and Perletta McSheen to Ralph Payne, 1747 Dec 5 (Box 5, Folder 167)
      - Tripartite indenture of release from Maitland & Boddington to John Mills et. al., 1766 Dec 5
    - Morgans Plantation
      - Lease from Sir Ralph Payne to Charles Pearce (2 copies), 1771 Nov 18 (Box 5, Folder 168-169)
      - Mortgage in fee from Sir Ralph Payne to Charles Pearce (2 copies), 1771 Nov 18, 19 (Box 5, Folder 170)
        See also: Oversize Parchment, Box 18, folder 447
      - Charles Pearce receipt to Sir Ralph Payne for L 10,000, 1772 Jul 7 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - New River Estate
      - Indenture and conveyance in four parts: Maynard and Fraser, 1789 Nov 17
    - Plantation in St. James's Parish
      - Indenture from Mary Elliott to Ralph Payne, 1747 Dec 30 (Box 6, Folder 172)
        Includes list of slaves
      - Indenture from Mary Elliott to Ralph Payne, 1747 Dec 31
    - Plantation in St. John's Parish
      - Tripartite indenture from Edward Jessup and members of the Dewitt family to Ralph Payne, 1745 May 27
    - Plantation in St. Thomas's Parish
      - Indentures between John Peterson George Burnett, 1758 Aug 24 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Plantation in Sulphur's Gutt
      - Indenture between Richard and Elizabeth Kirwan and Ralph Payne (2 copies), 1749 Feb 21
    - Richardson's Plantation
      - Indenture from John Richardson to Papillon Ball, 1739 Aug 2
    - Multiple Plantations in Nevis
      - Counterpart of grant of an annuity by Ralph Payne and Samuel Martin to Thomas Walter of Nevis, 1752 Dec 16
      - Deed of indenture from John Symonds to Ralph Payne, 1762 May 31
      - Indenture and release from Ralph Payne to Henry Wilmot, 1764 Jun 4
      - Indenture and release from Ralph Payne to Valentine Allott, 1768 Mar 3, 4
      - Indenture and release from Drewry Ottley to Ralph Payne, 1769 Jun 16
  - Passage Islands
    - Release from Edward Byam to Sir Ralph Payne (2 copies), 1773 Nov 26
      Transfer of the "Isle of Passage" and "the smaller Passage Islands, part of the Virgin Islands"
    - Letters Patent for the Island of Passage to the Honourable Edward Byam, Esq., 1774 Jul 13 (Box 6, Folder 174-176)
      Includes later correspondence and research notes concerning the title, 1860-88, undated
    - Note concerning the debt of Byam to Sir Ralph Payne, circa 1780 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - St. Croix
    - Plantations in Company with Alexander Cooper
      - Articles of Agreement for a Co-Partnership
      - Accounts for the Plantations in Company, 1758-1761 (Box 6, Folder 178)
      - Attestation of examination of the accounts, 1761 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 179)
        Signed by George Cooper, Frances Cooper, and John Willett
      - "A List of Sundrys wanted for the Plantations...in St. Croix", undated (Box 6, Folder 180)
        With additional note concerning coppers, undated
  - St. Christopher's (St. Kitts)
    - Land in Basseterre Town
      - Indenture between Peter Hende and John Davy Breholt, 1722 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 181)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Mrs. Catherine Fraize, 1726 Oct 25 (Box 6, Folder 182)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Anthony Du Roy, 1726 Sep 23 (Box 6, Folder 183)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Samuel Shipton, 1727 Apr 25 (Box 6, Folder 184)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and William Estridge, 1727 Oct 5 (Box 6, Folder 185)
        Concerns lands in "Deep Bay Town"
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Wavell Smith, 1728 Feb 20 (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and William Ashby, 1728 Apr 18 (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and John Harris, 1728 Apr 1 (Box 6, Folder 188)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Thomas Tyson, 1731 (Box 6, Folder 189)
        See also: Oversize Parchment, Box 18, folder 457
      - Fragment of bonds between Shipton and others, 1734 (Box 6, Folder 190)
      - Indenture between Peter Manning and Wavell Smith for the purchase of land in Basseterre, 1730 Jul 23 (Box 6, Folder 191)
      - Indenture between Sarah and Mary Guilhen and John Manning, 1731 Jun 26 (Box 6, Folder 192)
      - Indenture between John Willet and Stephen Payne, 1733 Dec 17 (Box 6, Folder 193)
      - Indenture between Jacob and Ann Martin and Ralph Payne, 1734 Mar 14 (Box 6, Folder 194)
      - Indenture between Wavell Smith and Zachariah Bourryau, 1734 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 195)
      - Indenture between Walton and Sarah O'Neal and Patrick Blake, 1734 Sep 20 (Box 6, Folder 196)
      - Indenture between Sarah and Mary Guilhen and Nicholas Parkinson, 1735 Dec 26 (Box 6, Folder 197)
      - Indenture between William and Christopher Stodard and Thomas Pilkington, 1736 Jul 20 (Box 6, Folder 198)
      - Articles of Purchase between His Majesty and Ralph Payne, 1737 Sep 20
      - Indenture between Tobias Wall and His Majesty's trustees for the purchase of lands in Basseterre, 1737 Sep 21 (Box 6, Folder 199)
      - Indenture between Peter Thomas and His Majesty's trustees for the purchase of lands in Basseterre, 1737 Sep 21 (Box 6, Folder 200)
      - Indenture between William Mathew, Gilbert Fleming, and John Willett and Henry Slingsby, 1737 Sep 21 (Box 6, Folder 201)
      - Indenture between William Mathew, Gilbert Fleming, and John Willett and Charles Milliken, 1737 Sep 21 (Box 6, Folder 202)
      - Indenture between William and Christopher Stoddard and Ralph Payne, 1742 Jun 16 (Box 6, Folder 203)
      - Indenture between Christopher Stoddard and Ralph Payne, 1744 Jul 20 (Box 6, Folder 204)
      - Indenture between John Willett and Henry Brouncker for a "dwelling-house", 1754 Jun 1 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Plantation and slaves in the Parish of St. Mary Cayenne
      - Indenture between John Ward and Thomas Mills, 1760 Dec 2
    - Plantation and slaves in the Parish of St. Paul Capisterre
      - Indenture between Dominick Trant and Joseph Phipps, 1727 Apr 13 (Box 7, Folder 206)
      - Indenture between John Helden and Gilbert Fleming, 1729 Dec 24
      - Indenture between John Lynch and Robert Henvill, 1743 Nov 5 (Box 7, Folder 207)
      - Assignation of bond from Dominick Henry Trant to several members of the Morphy family, 1760 Jul 15 (Box 7, Folder 208)
      - Indenture between Dominick Henry Trant of Montserrat and Archibald Esdail, 1768 Oct 12
        Includes inventory of "Slaves, buildings, mules, cattle, canes and plantation utinsils"
    - Plantation in the Parish of St. Thomas
      - Indenture between Susannah Mathew, Gilbert and Ann Fleming and John Maddox, 1737 Mar 5 (Box 7, Folder 209)
      - Indenture between John Reeah and Willet Payne, 1755 Sep 24 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Plantation in Trinity Palmetto Point
      - Bill of sale from Sarah Mullins to John Neale, 1717 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 211)
      - Mortgage from Valentine French to Martin Blake, 1736 Jul 16
      - Assignment by John Johnson to Drewry Ottley, 1737 Mar 31 (Box 7, Folder 212)
        Includes inventory of slaves and mules With additional notes on purchase
      - Mortgage in fee by John Johnson for Drewry Ottley, 1737 Mar 31 (Box 7, Folder 213)
      - Bond for performance of lease between Valentine French and Martin Blake, 1738 Apr 13
      - Indenture between Philip Audain and Zachariah Bourryau, 1740 Jun 11
    - Salt Ponds
      - Indenture between William Mathew, Gilbert Fleming, and John Willet and the Rev. Walter Thomas, 1742 Jun 16
      - Indenture between John and Mary Neal, Elizabeth Clay, Sarah Robinson, and Ann Williams and the Rev. Walter Thomas, 1746 Sep 5
      - Indenture between Richard Williams and the Rev. Walter Thomas, 1746 Sep 29 (Box 7, Folder 214)
      - Indenture between the Rev. Walter Thomas and Ralph Payne, 1747 Mar 26
    - Sandy Point
      - Grant of land in return for maintenance from Ann Garratt to Elizabeth Wishart, 1689 Feb 13 (Box 7, Folder 215)
      - Grant of land to Elizabeth Pew, 1698 Jan 10 (Box 7, Folder 216)
      - Sale of land to Stephen Payne, 1698 Jan 11 (Box 7, Folder 217)
      - Deed of gift from Ann Garratt to Elizabeth Wishart, 1699 May 29 (Box 7, Folder 218)
      - Indenture between Ann Garratt and Stephen Payne, 1704 Oct 8 (Box 7, Folder 219)
    - Sugar Mill in Frigate Bay
      - Indenture confirming articles of agreement between John Douglas, Peter Mitchell, and others regarding a joint boiling house, [1730 Feb?]
    - Sugar Mill in Irish Town (Basseterre)
      - Memorandum of Agreement between Ralph Payne and William Newton (2 copies), undated (Box 7, Folder 220)
      - Accounts between Ralph Payne and William Newton, 1746-1762, undated (Box 7, Folder 221-222)
      - Accounts and memoranda concerning the sugar mill, 1748-1755, undated (Box 7, Folder 223)
      - Business correspondence concerning the sugar mill, 1757-1764, undated (Box 7, Folder 224)
  - St. Vincent
    - Attested copy of a grant from King George III to William Fitzhugh of a plantation in the parish of St. David, 1768 Jul 8
      With diagram of land
    - Mortgage from William Fitzhugh to William Lee for L 3300, for the St. David parish plantation (2 copies), 1771 Jul 30 (Box 8, Folder 225-226)
    - Assignment of a debt of L 2360 on the estate of the late William Fitzhugh, from the executors of William Lee to William Lee Antonie, Esq., 1786 Jun 8 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Tobago
    - Duplicate mortgage by Cauldwell Craig Esq. to James Ballmer Esq., 1773 Jan 6
    - Last will and testament of Thomas Wilson of Tobago (wife Martha), 1802 Mar 12 (Box 8, Folder 228)
      Includes registration of will by Archbishop of Canterbury
  - Tortola
    - Release of lands on Tortola from Edward Byam to Sir Ralph Payne, 1773 Nov 24 (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Bargain and sale of lands on Tortola from Edward Byam to Sir Ralph Payne, 1773 Nov 26 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Unidentified and Incomplete
    - "Purchase of interests in Plantation, Buildings, 82 Slaves, Cattle, etc. in the West Indies" (incomplete), 1775
- Payne Family Personal Estate Papers, 1759-1855; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series IV contains documents relating to the settlement of the wills and legacies of members of the Payne family, particularly Sir Ralph Payne (d. 1763) and Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington. Folder 237 contains a detailed list of slaves owned by Lord Lavington and their planned dispositions on his death.
  - Ralph Payne (d. 1763?)
    - Estate
      - Last will and testament, 1759 Jul 25 (Box 9, Folder 231)
      - Attestation of witnesses to Ralph Payne's last will and testament, 1763 Jan 15 (Box 9, Folder 232)
      - Accounts with Truman, Neave & Willett, 1764-1768
      - Accounts with the estate of Thomas McClearney, 1764 (Box 9, Folder 233)
      - Accounts of Stephen Payne with the estate of Ralph Payne, 1764-1768 (Box 9, Folder 234)
      - Opinion of the Solicitor General in the matter of a lapsed legacy in Ralph Payne's will, 1776 May 30 (Box 9, Folder 235)
        Formal case; opinion in the hand of and signed by Alexander Wedderburn
      - Statement by Lord Lavington concerning the adminstration of his father's will, [ca. 1780]
  - Ralph Payne, Baron Lavington (1739-1807)
    - Annuity grant from Stephen Payne-Gallwey to Sir Ralph Payne on revenues of lands in Norfolk, 1790 Jun 2 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - List of slaves to be disposed of after Lord Lavington's death, undated (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - Stephen Payne (d. 1772?)
    - Last will and testament, 1768 Jul 13 (Box 9, Folder 238)
  - Sir William Payne-Gallwey
    - Bond from Sir William Payne-Gallwey to John Moseley, 1818 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - Estate settlement correspondence, 1823-1855 (Box 9, Folder 240)
- Other Business Papers, 1679-1802; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series V, Other Business Papers, is organized alphabetically by type of material and then chronologically within each type. Contents include seven appraisals or slaves, stock and other properties; a variety of financial contracts; a declaration of manumission; and a set of documents relating to a prolonged legal dispute over lands on Nevis from the 1750s. Many of these papers also concern members of the Payne, Payne-Gallwey, Ottley, and Adye families documented elsewhere in the collection.
  - Appraisals
    - "An inventory of the negroes, cattle, horses...", 1723 Dec 17 (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - "Appraisement of my negroes taken from the Salt Pond", 1748 Jul 25 (Box 10, Folder 242)
    - Appraisal of "seven Negroes", 1755 Sep 3 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - "Valued the above Negroes", 1757 Aug 2 (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - "List of slaves and stock as taken by Mr. Beck manager", 1781 Oct 20 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - "A list of Mssrs. Payne & Cooper's Negroes", undated (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - "A schedule & appraisement of the Negroes, stock, buildings, caines etc.", undated (Box 10, Folder 247)
  - Estate Plans
    - Plan of a plot of land surveyed by George Webbe, 1747 Jul 29 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - Plan of an estate in the Parish of Middle Island belonging to John Reeah, 1750 Oct 15 (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - Plan of a house, undated (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - Legal Documents
    - Articles of Agreement
      - Between the King and Christopher Stoddard (2 copies), 1726 Sep 23
      - Between John Brach and George Gordon, 1755 Sep 24 (Box 10, Folder 251)
      - Between Andrew Perrott and Thomas Winder, 1762 Feb 6 (Box 10, Folder 252)
      - Between Mary Payne and Ralph Payne, 1773 Jul 7 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Articles of Purchase
      - Between the King and Rev. Walter Thomas, 1732 May 9, Aug 10
    - Bills of Exchange
      - "Fraudulent bills of exchange in the possession of Gideon Franklin", 1799-1802 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Bonds
      - Ralph Payne to Dominick Trant, 1746 Jan 1 (Box 10, Folder 255)
      - Joseph Payne to Stephen Payne, 1750 Jun 1 (Box 10, Folder 256)
      - Stephen Payne to Martha Love, 1753 Apr 27 (Box 10, Folder 257)
      - William Well, Jr. to Ralph Payne, 1754 Dec 15 (Box 10, Folder 258)
      - Ralph Payne to John Stanley, 1764 Jul 2 (Box 10, Folder 259)
      - Archibald Esdaile, Edward Gilliard, and Thomas Thomas to Dominick Trant, 1768 Oct 12 (Box 10, Folder 260)
      - Andrew Hamilton to Ralph Payne, 1772 May 26 (Box 10, Folder 261)
      - Anthony Cunyngham to Ralph Payne, 1772 Oct 24 (Box 10, Folder 262)
      - Mary Payne to Ralph Payne, 1773 Jul 27 (Box 10, Folder 263)
      - George Ottley to William Simson and Daniel Bergman, 1776 Apr 4 (Box 10, Folder 264)
      - Stephen Payne Gallwey to Ralph Payne, 1781 Dec 17 (Box 10, Folder 265)
      - George Ottley to Daniel Bergman, 1783 Jun 12 (Box 10, Folder 266)
      - Ralph Payne to Daniel Bergman, 1797 Nov 12 (Box 10, Folder 267)
    - Cases
      - Will of John Douglas, 1748 Jun 4 (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - Depositions
      - By Richard Williams and William Brown concerning land boundaries, 1731 Dec 10 (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - Indentures
      - Between Drewry Ottley of Tobago and Ralph Payne, 1772, 1774 (Box 10, Folder 270-271)
      - Between Amand and Charity Benneville and Alexander Willock for an annuity, 1797 Dec 4 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Leases
      - From William Stapleton to Nicholas Raynsford, attorney for Stephen Bearcroft, 1679 Mar 21 (Box 10, Folder 273)
      - From Daniel O'Neal to Ralph Payne, 1750 Sep 20 (Box 10, Folder 274)
      - From the guardians of Janette Orton to Anthony Fahie, 1750 Oct 5 (Box 10, Folder 275)
      - From George Gordon to Willett Payne, 1756 May 8 (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Legacies
      - Release from John Pogson to Ralph Payne, executor of Stephen Adye's estate
      - Release of legacies from Abraham Charles Adye to executors of Henry Payne's estate, 1773 May 21 (Box 10, Folder 277)
      - Acknowledgment of receipt of money by William Woodley to executors of Stephen Payne's estate, 1774 Mar 10 (Box 10, Folder 278)
      - Release of legacy from John and Anne Audain to executors of Willett Payne's estate, 1786 Nov 28 (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - Letters of Attorney
      - Letter of attorney from John Willett to Richard Wilson, Thomas Mills, and Robert Colhoun, 1751 Jul 8 (Box 10, Folder 280)
      - Letter of attorney from Andrew Perrott to Stephen Payne, 1758 May 29 (Box 10, Folder 281)
      - Letter of attorney from Martha Love to Walter Griffiths, 1758 Nov 19 (Box 10, Folder 282)
      - Letter of attorney from Robert Gibbon to Stephen Payne, 1764 Jun 7 (Box 10, Folder 283)
      - Warrant of attorney from George Ottley to Daniel Bergman, 1783 (Box 10, Folder 284)
    - Manumission Documents
      - Declaration of manumission by Stephen Payne-Galwey regarding "a certain Negro Woman Slave, commonly called or known by the Name of Kitty", 1781 Nov 17 (Box 10, Folder 285)
    - Wills
      - Last will and testament of Charles Powell, 1710 Feb 11 (Box 10, Folder 286)
      - Last will and testament of William Penn, 1738 Aug 17 (Box 10, Folder 287)
      - Last will and testament of Bedingford Pogson, 1739 Nov 16 (Box 10, Folder 288)
      - Notes on the will of John Osten, undated (Box 10, Folder 289)
    - Other Legal Documents
      - Record of debt from William Johnson to James Bunyard, 1709 Sep 24 (Box 10, Folder 290)
      - Protested bill between James Cradock and John Willett, 1754 Apr 2 (Box 10, Folder 291)
      - Documents related to legal dispute between Thadeus Bridgwater and William and Samuel Clarke Pemberton over land on Nevis Island (9 items), 1756-1758 (Box 10, Folder 292-293)